Guide to the Hisham Khatib Collection of photographic prints AD.MC.030
Akkasah: Photography Archive (NYU Abu Dhabi)
- Palestine by Bonfils, F.M. Good et al, ref726 (Object Digital copy only: 030_ref400-ref421)
  - 837 - Plateau de Mizpa - Platform of Mizpa (a watchtower)., Circa 1867-1880; ref411; Bonfils, Felix; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: 030_ref400-ref421)
    Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Buildings; Palestine; French Writing; English Writing; Landscapes
  - 286 - Souk-El-Trouk, Tunis., Circa 1870-1900; ref412; Etablissements Photographiques de Neurdein Freres (ND Phot), Paris (France); 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: 030_ref400-ref421)
    Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Tunis, Tunisia; Street Lamps; Street Vendors; Men; French Writing; Markets; Shops; Signs/Signposts; Architecture; Streets/Roads; Men; Regional/National Dress; Turbans; Hats; Individual Portraits
  - Four photographs of people and animals., Circa 1870-1910; ref413; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: 030_ref400-ref421)
    Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Men; Women; Children; Animals; Camels; Regional/National Dress; Buildings; Streets/Roads
  - 334 - Eglise de la Nativité, intérieur - Church of the Nativity, interior., Circa 1867-1880; ref414; Bonfils, Felix; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: 030_ref400-ref421)
    Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Church of the Nativity; Churches; Religious Sites; Architecture; Buildings; Bethlehem; West Bank; Palestine; Religious Imagery; Religious Crosses; French Writing; English Writing
  - Fishermen at the shore of the Sea of Galillee., Circa 1867-1900; ref415; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: 030_ref400-ref421)
    Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Men; Children; Hats; Regional/National Dress; Boats/Ships; Landscapes; Mountains/Hills; Lakes; Sea of Galilee/Lake Tiberias; Palestine; Transportation; English Writing; Fishing; Galilee
  - Mont Thabor (Mount Tabor)., Circa 1867-1900; ref416; Scutschi, Lutuf; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: 030_ref400-ref421)
    Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Landscapes; Mountains/Hills; Individual Portraits; Outdoors; Men; Animals; Horses; Mount Tabor/Jabal at-Tur; English Writing; Palestine
  - 236 - Jaffa, vue de la mer (Port of Jaffa)., Circa 1867-1880; ref417; Bonfils, Felix; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: 030_ref400-ref421)
    Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Buildings; Seas; Jaffa; Palestine; Boats/Ships; Transportation; Docks/Piers/Jetties; Landscapes
  - Monastery of Mar Saba., Circa 1867-1880; ref418; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: 030_ref400-ref421)
    Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Buildings; Architecture; Monasteries/Convents; Mar Saba/The Holy Lavra of Saint Sabbas the Sanctified; Religious Sites; Bethlehem; West Bank; Palestine; Mountains/Hills; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Landscapes
  - Colonnade of Herod at Samaria (Sebastia)., Circa 1867-1880; ref419; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: 030_ref400-ref421)
    Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Individual Portraits; Men; Outdoors; Samaria/as-Sāmirah; Palestine; Architecture; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; English Writing; Regional/National Dress; Facial Hair; Turbans
  - A portrait of a man facing left, wearing a cape and a turban., Circa 1867-1900; ref420; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: 030_ref400-ref421)
    Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Turbans; Individual Portraits; Regional/National Dress; Men; Facial Hair
  - A city surrounded by empty land., Circa 1867-1900; ref421; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: 030_ref400-ref421)
    Albumen Prints; Landscapes; Buildings; Deserts; Mountains/Hills; Photographic Prints
- Palestine Exploration Fund 1866-67, ref727 (Object Digital Copy Only - 030_ref422-ref425)
  - A view of Nimrod Fortress (Qal'at al-Subeiba)., Circa 1865-1866; ref422; Phillips, Henry, Sergeant, Active 1865-1867; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital Copy Only - 030_ref422-ref425)
    Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Forts/Castles; English Writing; Landscapes; Buildings; Banias, Golan Heights; Nimrod Fortress; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Palestine; Mountains/Hills
  - Original PEF catalogue description of ref422, no date; ref423; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital Copy Only - 030_ref422-ref425)
    Printed Materials
  - A view of Chorazin archaeological site in Northern Palestine., 1866; ref424; Phillips, Henry, Sergeant, Active 1865-1867; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital Copy Only - 030_ref422-ref425)
    Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; English Writing; Buildings; Landscapes; Palestine; Galilee
  - A view of Chorazin archaeological site in Northern Palestine., 1866; ref425; Phillips, Henry, Sergeant, Active 1865-1867; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital Copy Only - 030_ref422-ref425)
    Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Palestine; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Landscapes; English Writing; Galilee
  - A view of the ruins of a synagogue at Tell Hum., 1866; ref426; Phillips, Henry, Sergeant, Active 1865-1867; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital Copy Only - 030_ref422-ref425)
    Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Landscapes; English Writing; Synagogues; Religious Sites; Buildings; Men; Regional/National Dress; Galilee; Palestine
  - A view of the Sea of Galilee in Northern Palestine., 1866; ref427; Phillips, Henry, Sergeant, Active 1865-1867; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital Copy Only - 030_ref422-ref425)
    Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Sea of Galilee/Lake Tiberias; Lakes; Landscapes; Palestine; Water
  - An aqueduct at Khan Minyeh, Plain of Ghuweir., 1866; ref428; Phillips, Henry, Sergeant, Active 1865-1867; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital Copy Only - 030_ref422-ref425)
    Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Men; Regional/National Dress; Landscapes; Palestine; English Writing; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Mountains/Hills
  - A view of Mount Arbel., 1866; ref429; Phillips, Henry, Sergeant, Active 1865-1867; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital Copy Only - 030_ref422-ref425)
    Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Mountains/Hills; Landscapes; Palestine; English Writing; Galilee; Golan Heights
  - A view looking down Wadi Hamam., 1866; ref430; Phillips, Henry, Sergeant, Active 1865-1867; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital Copy Only - 030_ref422-ref425)
    Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Landscapes; Mountains/Hills; English Writing; Palestine; Wadi Hamam, Galilee
  - A panoramic view of Jezreel., 1866; ref431; Phillips, Henry, Sergeant, Active 1865-1867; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital Copy Only - 030_ref422-ref425)
    Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; English Writing; Landscapes; Buildings; Palestine; Marj Ibn Āmir/Jezreel valley; Jebel Faqqua/Mount Gilboa
  - A panoramic view of Jezreel., 1866; ref432; Phillips, Henry, Sergeant, Active 1865-1867; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital Copy Only - 030_ref422-ref425)
    Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Landscapes; Mountains/Hills; Palestine; English Writing; Marj Ibn Āmir/Jezreel valley
  - A panoramic view of Mound of Beisan (Tell Beit She'an)., 1866; ref433; Phillips, Henry, Sergeant, Active 1865-1867; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital Copy Only - 030_ref422-ref425)
    Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Landscapes; Palestine; English Writing; Mountains/Hills; Baysan/Baisan/Bisan
  - A street of columns in Samaria (Sebastia, Nablus)., 1866; ref434; Phillips, Henry, Sergeant, Active 1865-1867; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital Copy Only - 030_ref422-ref425)
    Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Samaria/as-Sāmirah; Nablus; Palestine; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Buildings; English Writing; Architecture
  - An aerial view of Mount Ebal., 1866; ref435; Phillips, Henry, Sergeant, Active 1865-1867; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital Copy Only - 030_ref422-ref425)
    Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; English Writing; Nablus; Landscapes; Mountains/Hills; Jabal 'Aybāl/Mount Ebal, West Bank; Palestine
  - A view of a bedouin camp east of Nablus., 1866; ref436; Phillips, Henry, Sergeant, Active 1865-1867; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital Copy Only - 030_ref422-ref425)
    Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Bedouins; Landscapes; Nablus; West Bank; English Writing; Mountains/Hills; Palestine
  - A rock hewn tomb in Shuafat., 1866; ref437; Phillips, Henry, Sergeant, Active 1865-1867; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital Copy Only - 030_ref422-ref425)
    Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; English Writing; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Tombs/Mausoleums; Buildings; Palestine; Shuafat, East Jerusalem; Religious Sites
  - Threshing-floor on Damascus Road (between Tell el-Fūl and Mount Scopus)., 1867; ref438; Phillips, Henry, Sergeant, Active 1865-1867; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital Copy Only - 030_ref422-ref425)
    Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; English Writing; Landscapes; Jerusalem; Palestine
  - A view of the Jericho Plain (between Wady Qelt and Tell es-Sultan)., 1867; ref439; Phillips, Henry, Sergeant, Active 1865-1867; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital Copy Only - 030_ref422-ref425)
    Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Jericho; West Bank; Palestine; Landscapes; Mountains/Hills; English Writing; Wadi Qelt/Wadi Kelt
  - Tree (Ziziphus jujuba) in wadi at Ain Jidi (Ein Gedi)., 1867; ref440; Phillips, Henry, Sergeant, Active 1865-1867; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital Copy Only - 030_ref422-ref425)
    Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; English Writing; Landscapes; Mountains/Hills; Animals; Palestine; Ain Jidi/Ein Gedi; Oases
  - A group of people and animals gathered at the ford across the Jordan River (wady Nawaimeh)., 1867; ref441; Phillips, Henry, Sergeant, Active 1865-1867; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital Copy Only - 030_ref422-ref425)
    Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; English Writing; Jordan River; Rivers; Men; Children; Animals; Swimming; Palestine; Women; Water; Oases; Regional/National Dress; Horses; Group Portraits
  - A general view of Mount Nebo from the spring of Ain Neba, Jordan., 1867; ref442; Phillips, Henry, Sergeant, Active 1865-1867; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital Copy Only - 030_ref422-ref425)
    Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; English Writing; Landscapes; Mountains/Hills; Jabal Nībū/Mount Nebo, Jordan
  - Ruins of buildings with Ionic columns at Khurbet Es Suk, Jordan., 1867; ref443; Phillips, Henry, Sergeant, Active 1865-1867; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital Copy Only - 030_ref422-ref425)
    Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Jordan; English Writing
  - A view of Wadi Qelt., Circa 1865-1867; ref444; Phillips, Henry, Sergeant, Active 1865-1867; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital Copy Only - 030_ref422-ref425)
    Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Landscapes; Mountains/Hills; Wadi Qelt/Wadi Kelt; English Writing; Palestine
- Egypt - Zangaki, Arnoux and Sebah, ref728 (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref446-483)
  - No 208 - Grotte de l'Esbequie, Caire, Caire (Two men sitting in front of the grotto in Ezbekieh Gardens, Cairo)., Circa 1867-90; ref446; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref446-483)
    Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; French Writing; Caves; Men; Group Portraits; Outdoors; Buildings; Gardens; Al Azbakeyah (Cairo, Egypt); Parks; Fez/Tarboush; Facial Hair; Hats
  - Ecluse amont a Ismailia (A Lock at Ismailia)., Circa 1860-90; ref447; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref446-483)
    Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Ismailia, Egypt; Bridges; Boats/Ships; Transportation; Rivers
  - No 236 - Vue du Caire et Mosquée de Mohamed Aly (A view of Cairo and the Mosque of Muhammed Ali)., Circa 1860-90; ref448; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref446-483)
    Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Mosques; Religious Sites; Buildings; Architecture; Cairo, Egypt; French Writing
  - No 902 - Denderah Colonnade., Circa 1860-90; ref449; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref446-483)
    Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Egyptian Hieroglyphics; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Architecture; Buildings; French Writing; Dendera, Egypt
  - No 720 - Bazar des Mandarins (A group of people at the Bazaar of Mandarins, Egypt)., Circa 1860-90; ref450; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref446-483)
    Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Men; Women; Children; Girls; Boys; Group Portraits; Buildings; Architecture; French Writing; Regional/National Dress; Egypt; Outdoors; Men; Food; Head Covers/Veils
  - Plan du Canal Maritime de Suez (A map of the Suez Canal)., Circa 1870-90; ref451; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref446-483)
    Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Individual Portraits; Maps; Suez, Egypt; English Writing; French Writing; Pasha; Ismail, Pasha, Khedive of Egypt, 1830-1895; Tawfīq Pasha, Mohamed, Khedive of Egypt, 1852-1892; Lesseps, Ferdinand de (Marie, Comte), 1805-1894; Muhammad Ali, Pasha, 1769-1849; Saʻīd, Pasha, Viceroy of Egypt, 1822-1963
  - No 297 - Vue du Caire et mosquée Sultan Hassan (A view of Cairo and the Mosque of Sultan Hassan)., Circa 1860-90; ref452; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref446-483)
    Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Mosques; Religious Sites; Buildings; Architecture; Cairo, Egypt; French Writing; Mosque-Madrassa of Sultan Hassan
  - No 252 - Intérieur de la Mosquée de Mohamed (Interior of the Mosque of Muhammed Ali, Cairo)., Circa 1860-90; ref453; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref446-483)
    Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Mosques; Religious Sites; Architecture; Buildings; Cairo, Egypt; French Writing; English Writing; Mosque of Muhammad Ali Pasha
  - No 15 - Quai du Port Said (Quay at Port Said)., Circa 1860-90; ref454; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref446-483)
    Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Boats/Ships; Transportation; Port Said, Egypt; French Writing; English Writing; Seas; Mediterranean Sea; Crowds; Buildings; Ports; Landscapes
  - 655bis - Brindisi - Colonna Erculea (Column of the Harbour in Brindisi, Italy)., unknown date; ref455; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref446-483)
    Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; English Writing; Buildings; Architecture; Monuments/Memorials; Brindisi, Italy; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts
  - 649 - Galerie avec bassin du Palais de Choubra (A view of the pool of the Shubra Palace)., Circa 1850-80; ref456; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref446-483)
    Photographic Prints; Choubra/Shubra, Egypt; Palaces; Buildings; Architecture; Water; Ponds; Men; French Writing
  - No 372 - Palais d'Abdin, Caire (The Abdeen Palace, Cairo)., Circa 1860-90; ref457; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref446-483)
    Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Buildings; Architecture; French Writing; Palaces; Abdin, Cairo, Egypt; Streets/Roads; Street Lamps; Mosques
  - No 396 - Sphink et pyramide (A group of people and camels with the Sphinx and the Pyramids of Giza)., Circa 1860-90; ref458; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref446-483)
    Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; The Great Sphinx of Giza; Giza, Egypt; Pyramids; Statues/Sculptures; Architecture; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; French Writing; Men; Regional/National Dress; Camels; Animals
  - No 284 - Cour de la Mosquée El-Azhar, réunion des théologies, Caire (Reunion of the theologies at the Court of the Al-Azhar Mosque, Cairo)., Circa 1860-90; ref459; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref446-483)
    Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Cairo, Egypt; Mosques; Religious Sites; Men; Regional/National Dress; Turbans; Architecture; Buildings; French Writing
  - 261 - A view of the Mosque of Muhammed Ali, Cairo., Circa 1860-90; ref460; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref446-483)
    Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Mosques; Religious Sites; Architecture; Buildings; Mosque of Muhammad Ali Pasha; Citadel, Cairo, Egypt; Tombs/Mausoleums; Cemeteries
  - No 344 - Pont de Kasr-el-Nil, Caire (Boats near the Qasr El Nil Bridge, Cairo)., Circa 1860-90; ref461; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref446-483)
    Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Bridges; Boats/Ships; Transportation; Cairo, Egypt; Nile River; Rivers; Palm Trees; Buildings; Architecture
  - No 439 - Serapis passant la courbe de Chantier (A ship sailing along a river)., Circa 1860-90; ref462; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref446-483)
    Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Boats/Ships; Transportation; Rivers; French Writing; Landscapes; Transportation; Water; Coast
  - No 31 - Malabar passant la courbe d'el Guirs (A ship sailing along a river)., Circa 1860-90; ref463; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref446-483)
    Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Boats/Ships; Transportation; Rivers; French Writing; Men; Landscapes; Coast; Water
  - No 558 - A group of kettle drum players riding camels., Circa 1860-90; ref464; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref446-483)
    Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Camels; Animals; Men; Musical Instruments; Musicians; Children; Regional/National Dress; Streets/Roads; Group Portraits; Facial Hair
  - Minarets of El-Muayyad at Bab Zuweila., unknown date; ref465; Lehnert & Landrock; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref446-483)
    Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Cairo, Egypt; Mosques; Buildings; Architecture; Men; English Writing; Children; Carriages/Coaches; Transportation; Turbans; Regional/National Dress; Religious Sites; Streets/Roads; Boys
  - 171 - Ismaïlia ecluse Amont (A lock at Ismailia)., unknown date; ref466; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref446-483)
    Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; French Writing; Men; Rivers; Ismailia, Egypt; Buildings; Dams/Barrages; Streets/Roads; Buildings; Water; Fez/Tarboush; Hats; Individual Portraits
  - No 455 - Phare de Port Said (Lighthouse at Port Said)., Circa 1860-90; ref467; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref446-483)
    Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Ports; Lighthouses; Boats/Ships; Transportation; Buildings; Port Said, Egypt; Seas; Mediterranean Sea; French Writing; Individual Portraits
  - No 121 - Place de Lesseps à Port Said (Lesseps Square in Port Said)., Circa 1860-90; ref468; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref446-483)
    Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Hotels; Buildings; Architecture; Port Said, Egypt; French Writing; Gardens; Churches; Ports; Streets/Roads; Street Lamps
  - Rade de Port Said (Aerial view of a roadstead in Port Said)., Circa 1860-90; ref469; Arnoux, Hippolyte (Circa 1860-1890); 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref446-483)
    Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Boats/Ships; Transportation; Port Said, Egypt; Seas; Mediterranean Sea; Buildings; Ports; Landscapes
  - Intérieur de la mosquée d'Amrou, au vieux Caire (Interior of the Amr Ibn Al Aas Mosque, Cairo)., Circa 1860-90; ref470; Arnoux, Hippolyte (Circa 1860-1890); 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref446-483)
    Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; French Writing; Mosques; Religious Sites; Architecture; Buildings; Cairo, Egypt; Mosque of Amr ibn al-As
  - Intérieur de l'Eglise Cophte Ste Marie, au Vieux Cairo, 733 (Interior of the Hanging Church, Cairo)., Circa 1860-90; ref471; Arnoux, Hippolyte (Circa 1860-1890); 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref446-483)
    Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; French Writing; Religious Sites; Churches; Cairo, Egypt; Carpets/Rugs; Chandeliers; Saint Virgin Mary's Coptic Orthodox Church (Hanging Church); Architecture
  - Intérieur de la mosquée Kail Bey, 700 (Interior of the Kail Bey Mosque, Cairo)., Circa 1860-90; ref472; Arnoux, Hippolyte (Circa 1860-1890); 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref446-483)
    Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Religious Sites; Mosques; Cairo, Egypt; French Writing; Architecture; Buildings; Men; Turbans; Regional/National Dress; Mosque and Tomb of Sultan al-Ashraf Qaitbay
  - No 700 - Intérieur de la mosquée Kail Bey, Caire (Interior of the Kail Bey Mosque, Cairo)., unknown date; ref473; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref446-483)
    French Writing; Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Religious Sites; English Writing; Architecture; Mosques; Buildings; Cairo, Egypt; Men; Regional/National Dress; Turbans; Mosque and Tomb of Sultan al-Ashraf Qaitbay
  - No 737 - Tombeau de Caïd Bey, Caire (The tomb of Kait Bey, Cairo)., Circa 1860-90; ref474; Arnoux, Hippolyte (Circa 1860-1890); 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref446-483)
    Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; French Writing; Cairo, Egypt; Tombs/Mausoleums; Mosque and Tomb of Sultan al-Ashraf Qaitbay; Arabic Writing; Arabic Calligraphy; Mosques; Religious Sites
  - No 791 - Tombeau de Mehemet Ali à la Citadelle, Caire (The tomb of Muhammad Ali of Egypt, Cairo)., Circa 1860-90; ref475; Arnoux, Hippolyte (Circa 1860-1890); 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref446-483)
    Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; French Writing; Tombs/Mausoleums; Carpets/Rugs; Arabic Calligraphy; Citadel, Cairo, Egypt; Mosque of Muhammad Ali Pasha; Coffins/Caskets; Mosques; Religious Sites
  - No 613 - Intérieur de la Mosquée Mehemet Ali, Caire (Interior of the Mosque of Muhammed Ali, Cairo)., Circa 1860-90; ref476; Arnoux, Hippolyte (Circa 1860-1890); 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref446-483)
    Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; French Writing; Mosques; Religious Sites; Citadel, Cairo, Egypt; Architecture; Mosque of Muhammad Ali Pasha
  - No 703 - Intérieur de la mosquée Touloun, Caire (Interior of the Mosque of Ibn Tulun, Cairo)., Circa 1860-90; ref477; Arnoux, Hippolyte (Circa 1860-1890); 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref446-483)
    Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; French Writing; Mosques; Individual Portraits; Outdoors; Religious Sites; Men; Regional/National Dress; Turbans; Architecture; Mosque of Ibn Tulun; Cairo, Egypt
  - No 765 - Cour intérieur de la mosquée Touloun, Caire (Courtyard of the Mosque of Ibn Tulun, Cairo)., Circa 1860-90; ref478; Arnoux, Hippolyte (Circa 1860-1890); 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref446-483)
    Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Men; Regional/National Dress; Turbans; Religious Sites; Mosques; Buildings; Architecture; French Writing; Mosque of Ibn Tulun; Cairo, Egypt
  - No 756 - Vue d'ensemble de l'intérieur de l'Eglise Cophte, vieux Caire (Overview of the interior of the Coptic Church, Old Cairo)., Circa 1860-90; ref479; Arnoux, Hippolyte (Circa 1860-1890); 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref446-483)
    Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Cairo, Egypt; Religious Imagery; Religious Sites; Churches; Arabic Writing; French Writing; Saint Virgin Mary's Coptic Orthodox Church (Hanging Church); Architecture
  - A panoramic view of Cairo and the Mosque of Sultan Hassan., Circa 1860-90; ref480; Arnoux, Hippolyte (Circa 1860-1890); 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref446-483)
    Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Mosques; Religious Sites; Buildings; Architecture; Cairo, Egypt; Mosque-Madrassa of Sultan Hassan